A Guide to the Correspondence Between James Branch Cabell and Burton Rascoe, 1917-1957
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Correspondence Between James Branch Cabell and Burton Rascoe, 1917-1957
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-a
This collection consists of 390 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was exchanged on 1959 Feb 5.
Scope and Content Information
In this correspondence between James Branch Cabell and Burton Rascoe, 1917-1957, the men discuss reviews, essays, American writers, and their work. Included in the collection are a page proof of Smire; a court ruling in favor of Jurgen and a court indictment against Robert McBride and Co.; and a chapter fragment, "Confusions of the Golden Travel," from Something About Eve.
Among the correspondents are Mabel McElliott, Jesse Quitman, Rupert O. Hughes, Lewis Galantier, Mitchell S. Buck, Ellen Glasgow, Emily Tapscott Clark Balch, and John Craig.
These letters are photocopies of originals in the University of Pennsylvania Library.
Contents List
- Letter from Burton Rascoe to James Branch Cabell 1917 Dec 31, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Mar 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Mar 13, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Mar 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Apr 5, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Apr 13, TLS. [w/auto. postscript.] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Apr 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Apr 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Apr 23, TLS. 3 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Apr 29, TLS. [Encl. "Ultra Crepidam," a 4 p. TMs (2 copies), 7 p. TMs, "Anti-Cabellum" by Rupert Hughes, and 1 p. TMs, "An Epilogue" by J.B.C.] 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Apr 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 May 9, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 May 17, Telegram
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 May 17, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 May 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Jun 4, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Jun 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Jun 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe [1918 Jul 20], ALS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Aug 13, ALS. 2 p.
- Letter from Rascoe to J.B.C. 1918 Aug 29, TLS. 4 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Sep 10, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Sep 20, Telegram
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Oct 8, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to__________Cook 1918 Oct 8, TL. [w/note at bottom from Cook to Rascoe.] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Oct 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Nov 5, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Nov 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1918 Dec 28, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe [1918], ALS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe [1918], ALS. 3 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Jan 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Jan 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Feb 15, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Mar 25, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to [Lewis] Galantière 1919 Mar 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Apr 24, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Jun 21, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Jul 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Jul 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Aug 10, ALS. 4 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Sep 24, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Guy Holt 1919 Oct 4, TL. [Fragment.] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Oct 17, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Oct 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Nov 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Nov 22, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Nov 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1919 Dec 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1920 Jan 2, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1920 Jan 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1920 Feb 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Robert McBride and Co. to J.B.C. 1920 Mar 1, TL. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1920 Apr 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1920 May 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe [1920] May 13, Telegram.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to J.B.C. 1920 Sep 15, TL. [First page.] 1 p.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to Mitchell S. Buck 1920 Oct 19, TL. [Copy for Guy Holt.] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1920 Nov 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1921 Jan 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1921 Jun 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1921 Aug 20, ALS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1921 Sep 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1921 Oct 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1921 Nov 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1921 Nov 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to J.B.C. 1921 Nov 22, TL. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1921 Dec 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe l922 Apr 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1922 Apr 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1922 May 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1922 Aug 10, ALS. 1 p.
- Judge Nott's findings in favor of Jurgen, 1922 Oct 19, Court ruling. [w/1920 January 14, 1 p. court indictment against Robert McBride and Co.] 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1922 Oct 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1922 Nov 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe [1922], ALS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1923 Jan 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1923 Sep 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1923 Oct 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe [1923], ALS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1924 Jun 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1924 Oct 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Ellen Glasgow and J.B.C. to Rascoe [1926], APCS.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Mar 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Apr 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 April 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 May 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 May 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Jun 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from "Confusions of the Golden Travel" [1927], TMs. [Fragment of chapter from Something About Eve.] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Jul 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Jul 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Aug 15, Telegram.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Aug 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Sep 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1927 Dec 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1928 May 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1928 Oct 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1929 Mar 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1929 Mar 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1929 Apr 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1929 Apr 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1929 Jun 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1930 Jan 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1930 Jan 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1930 Feb 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1930 Mar 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1930 Apr 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1930 May 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1930 May 27, TL. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1930 Jun 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. 1930 Oct 11, TLS. [w/envelope.] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1932 Jan 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1932 Nov 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1932 Dec 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1932 Dec 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1933 May 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1933 Sep 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1933 Sep 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1933 Dec 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1933 Dec 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1934 Mar 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1934 Mar 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to J.B.C. 1934 Jul 7, TL. 1 p.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to Emily Clarke 1934 Jul 7, TL. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1934 Dec 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1935 Sep 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1935 Nov 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Mar 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Mar 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Apr 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Jul 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to J.B.C. 1936 Jul 9, TL. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Jul 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to J.B.C. 1936 Jul 16, TL. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Jul 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from [M.J.]_______ to Rascoe 1936 Jul 23, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to J.B.C. 1936 Jul 24, TL. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Jul 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Aug 6, TLS. [2 copies] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Aug 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Sep 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Oct 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Oct 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from [Rascoe] to J.B.C. 1936 Nov 13, TL. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Nov 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Nov 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Nov 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Dec 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Dec 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1936 Dec 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Jan 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Feb 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Mar 7, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Mar 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Apr 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Apr 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 May 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 May 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 May 31, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Oct 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Oct 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1937 Dec 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1938 Jan 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1938 Jan 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1938 Feb 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1938 Feb 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1938 Mar 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1938 Mar 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1938 Mar 30, TLS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1938 Apr 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1939 Jan 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to ______ Eshleman 1939 Feb 12, TL. [trans.] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1940 Jan 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1940 Feb 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1942 Jan 10, TLS. 1 p.
- News release, re: J.B.C., "Being an Author is Hard on the Feet" 1942 Jan 21, TMS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1942 Feb 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1942 Feb 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1942 Feb 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1942 Nov 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1942 Nov 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1943 Sep 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Philip _______ 1945 Oct 27, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1946 Jun 9, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1947 Apr 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1947 Oct 8, TLS. [2 copies] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1947 Oct 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Hazel and Burton Rascoe 1950 Jun 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1950 Jul 4, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1952 Apr 6, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1953 Feb 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Margaret Cabell to Rascoe 1953 May 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Margaret and James Cabell to Rascoe 1953 Jun 3, TLS. 5 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1953 Jul 24, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1953 Aug 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe [1953], TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1955 Sep 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1955 Sep 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe 1955 Nov 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Hazel Rascoe 1957 Mar 23, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Margaret Cabell to Hazel Rascoe [1957 Mar], ALS. 2 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Hazel Rascoe 1957 Apr 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Hazel Rascoe 1957 May 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Card from Margaret and James Cabell to______ n.d., Christmas-card
- Letter from J.B.C. to Rascoe n.d., TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Molly__________ to Rascoe n.d., TN. 1 p.
- J.B.C.'s report on Rascoe to the Guggenheim Foundation n.d., TMs. 1 p.
- Letter from John Craig to Rascoe n.d., ANS. 2 p.
- Letter from John Craig to Rascoe n.d., 19 ANS. 1 p. each